Jonas Duri

Senior Frontend Developer

40215 Düsseldorf, NRW, Germany

E-Mail Medium Twitter LinkedIn Github Dribbble Homepage

I am a senior frontend developer at Boxine GmbH in Duesseldorf, Germany. I bring ideas to life from wireframe sketches to functional prototypes to polished features. With a background in sales and expert web frontend development skills I helped to build products for corporations, e-commerce startups, digital agencies and various client during my freelance career. I am a strong believer in the MVP approach with quick iterations, early testing and continuous shipping.

Occasionally I write about web development. I only published one article in the recent past. I hope to find the time to bring more ideas to paper in the future.

• Building A Landing Page With Webpack 4

Human Languages

- English fluent
- German native

Programming Languages

- Javascript (95% of my daily business)
- Typescript
- PHP
- HTML
- CSS

Hobby Programming Languages

- Python
- Rust

Technologies

- JavaScript, TypeScript, Nodejs
- Babel and other transpilers, Webpack, Rollup, Parcelis, Gulp, Grunt
- Jest, Mocha, Jasmine, Puppeteer, Karma, Plain old "assert"
- HTML 5, Single Page Applications, Browser APIs, Sass, less, stylus, css custom properties
- Webcomponents, React, Angular, Serverless Framework, Expressjs, Hapijs
- Redux State Management, Observable Pattern, Finite State Machines for UI Components, Server side rendering (SSR) with React and Angular, Internationalization

- AWS Lambda, Google Cloud Functions
- Gitlab CI, Circle Ci
- Gitlab, Github, AWS, Google Cloud, Netlify, Artifactory, Jira, Confluence, Launch Darkly (Feature Flag and A/B Testing), Contentful (Headless Content Management)

Work Experience

Senior Frontend Developer April 2018- current

Boxine GmbH | [https://tonies.com]

While transitioning from an external service provider to an internal development team I helped our Head of Cloud Development to build a strong development team and successfully migrate the previous Python (Django) application to a REST API Backend and a React Frontend. We rewrote the existing application to use modern Javascript technologies like *React* and *styled-components*. A development preview is available at https://meine.ga.tonie.cloud.

- Evaluate technologies and its potential strategic impact.
- Conduct interviews with developers.
- Create code challenges and evaluate results.
- Share knowledge of building modern web applications with other developers.
- Creating and maintaining a custom React component library for UI elements.

Senior Frontend Developer September 2017- March 2018

Stepstone Continental Europe | https://stepstone.com

Creating a real-time messaging web application for job seekers and recruiters.

- Creating a custom build system to optimize client bundles.
- Develop a transition strategy for moving the current Angular 4 application to a web components based SPA.
- Developing framework independent custom elements which can be shared across projects.
- Conduct interviews with frontend developers.
- Create code challenges and evaluate results.

Frontend Developer November 2016- September 2017

Ubisoft Blue Byte | https://ubisoft.com

Building the game to web application for Ubisoft's AAA title "For Honor" with TypeScript leveraging Angular and Webcomponents technology.

- Creating a modular, component based application using JavaScript, TypeScript and the Angular framework.
- Optimizing application structure and software design.
- Creating JavaScript canvas application features.
- Creating an advanced Webpack based build system which fits into a complex corporate infrastructure.
- Working on features like displaying in-game player statistics in a web frontend.

- Creating prototypes with React and Redux to render canvas applications.
- Building JavaScript libraries with Rollup.js using advanced tree-shaking and dead code elimination techniques.

Frontend Developer August 2015- November 2016

Mapudo GmbH | https://mapudo.com

I helped to create Mapudo's ecommerce platform for digital steel trading. In close collaboration with stakeholders and product owners I helped to develop the platform from MVP to release.

- Implementing the front-end application using JavaScript, TypeScript and the AngularJS framework.
- Writing unit test for the AngularJS application
- PHP development with the Symfony framework
- Creating design proposals together with stakeholders and implement features according to functional and visual requirements.
- Measuring performance of features with tools like Google Analytics, Lead Inspector, Heap.
- Assist Mapudo's online marketing with SEO and SEA by optimizing the JavaScript application to be search engine friendly and play nicely with Google Adwords and Mailchimp.
- Using and improving Mapudo's Docker container setup

Frontend Developer August 2014- August 2015

Digital Agency OYGO | https://oygo.com/

Together with stakeholders and product owners I developed a technical prototype for a SaaS product providing customers an easy way to manage closed WiFi portals.

- Creating a custom Drag & Drop based content management system for closed WiFi portals.
- Developed WiFi portals for customers like Real, QSC, Breuninger, Microsoft's Digital Eatery.
- Developed product marketing and promotion websites for Johnson & Johnson's brands "bebe Young Care" and "bebe More".
- Communication with our customers to improve the product and focus development efforts.

Freelance Webdesigner & Developer January 2013- August 2014

As a freelance web developer and designer I provided full service for clients to help them build websites for their business.

- Concept, design and development for the website of Bridge Expert Solutions, a consulting business based in Munich - http://www.bridge-expert.net
- Concept, design and development for the website of Equintus GmbH, a former real estate business based in Düsseldorf. Now German Sherpa http://www.germansherpa.com/
- Small logo and business card design projects.

Sergeant OR-5 2009

German Army in Oldenburg, Schleswig-Holstein

Sergeant career in professional military service. Unfit for duty after a knee injury

Metro Cash & Carry GmbH | https://www.metro-cc.com/

During my apprenticeship I gained in depth knowledge of all tools and traits a trader should have. I learned the principles of marketing, distribution chain management and accounting. I developed the skill to always value the details while focusing on the result. This apprenticeship helps me in my recent positions to keep an eye on budgets and profitability and to see development efforts from a business perspective.

Education

College Niederrhein in Krefeld, Germany 2009- 2014

Applied computer science - no graduation

Walter Eucken trade school in Düsseldorf, Germany 2006 - 2009

Wholesale and foreign trade

Franz-Haniel High School in Duisburg, Germany 1996 - 2006

Advanced technical college certificate